Ashley Darzinikas-Walters

98 Southeast Drive, Hamburg PA 19526 570-691-5262, Adarz482@live.kutztown.edu

Middle and High School English Teacher

Creative, enthusiastic, and student-centered educator who is driven to meet each student's needs through delivery of an engaging and challenging education.

Qualifications

- Differentiated Instruction
- Inclusion of multiple intelligences
- Technology Integration
- Special Education/IEP Experience

- Club Advisor
- Co-teaching/Team Concept
- Data Analysis
- Active/Hands-on Learning Approach

Professional Experience

7th Grade Language Arts Teacher

Cocalico Middle School, Denver PA

January 2015-Present

Teacher for seventh grade Literacy Workshop and Communication Arts courses. Developed classroom strategies to increase student engagement and foster a positive classroom community. Collaborated with colleagues to enrich curriculum. Scaffolded instruction to ensure student success. Analyzed data to support individualized instruction.

Highlights

- Collaborative Learning
- Common core lesson and assessment alignment
- Interactive Notebook for independent note taking
- Literature Circles
- Mini-thon, Oratory Celebration, Junior Honors Society, and Honors Reception Volunteer
- Mythology Day Co-Organizer

9th & 12th Grade English Teacher

Fleetwood Area High School, Fleetwood PA

January 2011-December 2014

Teacher for ninth and twelfth grade English courses and ninth through twelfth grade family and consumer sciences. Held multiple long term substitute positions. Designed lessons based on Gardner's Multiple Intelligences, cooperative learning, and technology integration. Increased experience in working with learning support, emotional support, and gifted students.

Highlights

- Academic and Accelerated 9th grade English
- Academic 12th grade English
- Creative Writing, Public Speaking, and Sports Media English Electives
- Family & Relationship Dynamics and Independent Living Courses
- Culinary Essentials and Healthy Eating Electives

9th Grade English Teacher

North Schuylkill Junior-Senior High School, Ashland PA

February-June 2013

Teacher for ninth grade general, academic, and honors English and mythology elective. Differentiated instruction and curriculum to meet each class's and student's needs; employed active learning to increase student participation and engagement. Collaborated with parents to support students' needs.

Highlights

- · Collaborative Learning
- Unit and assessment development

- Co-teaching
- Essay Structure/Writing

Ashley Darzinikas-Walters

98 Southeast Drive, Hamburg PA 19526 570-691-5262, Adarz482@live.kutztown.edu

10th through 12th Grade Communications Teacher

Reading Area High School, Reading PA

October-December, 2011

Teacher for Video Communications elective. Incorporated project based learning for authentic learning experience. Fostered a positive and creative classroom environment through student collaboration.

Highlights

- imovie/Mac technology
- Daily in-school suspension supervisor
- Library Assistant

- Co-Advisor: Project Peace
- Co-organized student trip to Philadelphia to meet with student/community activists

Educational Background

Kutztown University of Pennsylvania, Kutztown PA

- Bachelor of Science in Education, Secondary Education English December 2010
- Summa Cum Laude: 3.87 GPA
- English 7-12 Certification

Honors

- Student Teacher of the High School Placement/ Semester
- Sigma Tau Delta- International English Honor Society
- Emma Richards-Bausch Award in Literary Criticism
- Presenter: 11th Annual Undergraduate Research and Creativity Conference
- Faculty Award for Undergraduate Academic Excellence

Related Experience

Ballet Instructor

Culture Shock Performing Arts Center, Hamburg, PA

August 2014-Present

- Teach students, ages six through eighteen, in the art of dance and ballet
- · Foster creativity, self-esteem, and cooperation

SAT/ACT Tutor, Study Skills Tutor

Huntington Learning Center, Wyomissing, PA

March-December 2014

- Prepared students for ACT and SAT exams through individualized instruction
- Strengthened students' reading, writing, and test-taking skills
- Supported students through reading/math skills instruction

Camp Director

KE Camps, Lebanon, PA

Summer 2014

- Developed, organized, and facilitated activities in the areas of art, science, creative writing, teamwork, and athletics
- Managed counselor staff and communicated with parents daily
- Ensured a stimulating environment where campers were encouraged to try new activities

English Club President and Secretary

Kutztown University, Kutztown PA

January-December 2010

- Developed and facilitated "Show It Young Poet" writing contest and reading celebration, open to local area high school students
- Organized bus trip to National Book festival in Washington D.C.
- · Organized National Poetry Month campus poetry reading event

References available upon request